Tomislav Fičko

Telecommunications Graduate

An independent and self-motivated graduate student with competence in management and team leadership. A hard worker with experience in volunteering and various student jobs, driven by continuous learning and the strive to always better oneself.



ficko.tomislav@gmail.com

+385 98 908 5508

Zagreb, Croatia

linkedin.com/in/tomislav-ficko

tomislav.ficko

WORK EXPERIENCE

Solution Engineer Infobip

07/2019 - 06/2020

Testing Mobile Identity APIs

- Communication with mobile network operators
- Analysis of technical documentation

Contact: Gordana Čoh Stjepanović - gordana.coh@infobip.com

Android Engineer Infinum

03/2019 - 04/2019

Zagreb, Croatia

Zagreb, Croatia

- Created an application using the MVVM architecture (used Dagger2, Retrofit, Moshi and RxJava)
- Took part in team meetings. The used collaboration tools include Productive, Slack

Java Software Engineering Intern Infobip

Vodnian, Croatia

- Assigned with creating the front-end part of a private social network, got a chance to work with ReactJS
- · Worked on the back-end part of a Spring application which dealt with e-mail communication and took part in feature planning
- My team employed Scrum and I took part in meetings and Sprint plannings. The used collaboration tools include Git, Slack, JIRA, BitBucket and Confluence

Java Software Engineering Intern Infobip

Zagreb, Croatia

- Connected internal applications to various web services (used Spring, REST, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap). Throught this task I got introduced to front-end development
- Created new Spring application which posted information from JIRA and BitBucket about a new feature releases to a website and Slack

EDUCATION

Telecommunications and Informatics Graduate Study University of Zagreb Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing

10/2018 - 06/2021

Zagreb, Croatia

• MSc Seminar: "Reduction of electricity consumption using Smart Outlets within Smart Homes

Telecommunications and Informatics Undergraduate Study University of Zagreb Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing

10/2014 - 06/2018

Zagreb, Croatia

- BSc Thesis: "Integrating IoT Platform OpenHAB with symbIoTe Cloud Framework"
- BSc Seminar: "Internet protocols and the transition mechanisms towards IPv6"

SKILLS

Kotlin Android

Scrum

Leadership

Effective communication

Teamwork

Management

Initiative

Calmnes

Organization

LANGUAGES

English



German









PROJECTS

Soft Skills Academy Zagreb - CR organizer (10/2019 - 12/2019)

- Arranging partnerships with companies
- Communication with partners

IoT Workshop - Main organizer (11/2018 - 01/2019)

- Coordinating team and logistics, assigning tasks
- Communication with companies and lecturers
- Held opening and closing speeches

ORGANIZATIONS

IT Team Lead - EESTEC LC Zagreb (08/2020 - 07/2021)

PR Coordinator - EESTEC LC Zagreb (08/2018 - 07/2019)

Organizing PR activities and leading the PR team

Member of EESTEC LC Zagreb (03/2017 - Present)

 $Electrical\ Engineering\ Students' European\ Association$

CERTIFICATES

SmartSoc Blended Mobility 2020 (03/2020 - 09/2020)

"Green Mobility" startup, a solution for bicycle parking in cities

Breaking Web Workshop (02/2020) Web development workshop in Ankara, Turkey

Soft Skills Academy Zagreb (12/2018)

Leadership training (Conflict management, Presentation skills, Time management, Design thinking)

Code App Level Up 4 Workshop (03/2018) Angular workshop in Skopje, Macedonia

COMPETITIONS

Try{Code}Catch Hackaton (05/2018)

Team leader and backend Java developer (Spring Boot)